<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Home</title>
    <link>https://vatanparast.xyz/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 23:10:58 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vatanparast.xyz/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Goodbye Twitter </title>
      <link>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 23:10:58 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/twitter/</guid>
      <description>Twitter is one of the most popular social media platforms. Recent purchase and changes in its leadership concerned many Twitter users as they moved away from it and migrated to other Fediverse platforms like Mastodon.
I have been a Twitter user since 2015, and while I was not an active user all the time, it was an online environment in which I cloud connect with friends and people I met in real life and share moments with them.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Twitter is one of the most popular social media platforms. Recent purchase and changes in its leadership concerned many Twitter users as they moved away from it and migrated to other Fediverse platforms like <a href="https://joinmastodon.org/">Mastodon</a>.</p>
<p>I have been a Twitter user since 2015, and while I was not an active user all the time, it was an online environment in which I cloud connect with friends and people I met in real life and share moments with them. Because Twitter is FREE and not charging users for the service, it comes with ads. However, numerous third-party legal apps are developed that let you access Twitter feeds without seeing ads and distractions, and Twitter&rsquo;s API provides this.</p>
<p>Last Thursday, Twitter revoked API access to those apps like Tweetbot without proper notice or official announcement. And worse, when the developers reached Twitter on the issue, the feedback was absolute silence, even not <del>a</del> single word from <a href="https://www.theverge.com/2023/1/13/23553161/third-party-twitter-clients-apps-outage-twitterific-tweetbot">Mr. Musk</a>. It is a speculation that Twitter &lsquo;intentionally&rsquo; blocked those apps.</p>
<p>As <a href="https://daringfireball.net/linked/2023/01/14/information-twitter-slack-confirmation">John Gruber nicely wrote</a>:</p>
<blockquote>
<p>Twitter can of course do what it wants, and Musk owns Twitter so he can do what he wants. But pulling the plug on these clients and ghosting everyone on communications about it is so absurdly disrespectful. Zero respect for the users for those apps, zero respect for the developers behind them — many of whom had been building on the Twitter platform for 10-15 years. Just a clown show.</p>
</blockquote>
<p>I have been using Tweetbot since 2016, but it stopped working last Thursday.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/tweetbot.jpg" type="" alt="Tweetbot"  /></p>
<p>It is time to use open platforms and self-hosted social networking services like <a href="https://github.com/mastodon/mastodon">Mastodon</a>. I deactivated my Twitter account, and sorry to miss contact with friends. You can now find me <a href="https://ecoevo.social/@vatan">here</a>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Sorbitol wash of DNA extraction of autumn leaves</title>
      <link>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/sorbitol-wash/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Jan 2023 22:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/sorbitol-wash/</guid>
      <description>DNA extraction from fresh and young spring leaves is easy using the inexpensive CTAB method or expensive column kits. However, when it comes to DNA extraction from degraded autumn tree leaves, pre-wash before the CTAB step is required to get rid of the secondary compounds, which pass through to the final stages. The results would be genomic DNA contaminated with polysaccharides, polyphenols, etc.
Ulmus autumn leaves I tried TNE (Tris, NaCl, EDTA) buffer as a pre-wash before CTAB for Ulmus species, but DNA was not precipitating well enough after keeping overnight at -20C.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>DNA extraction from fresh and young spring leaves is easy using the inexpensive CTAB method or expensive column kits. However, when it comes to DNA extraction from degraded autumn tree leaves, pre-wash before the CTAB step is required to get rid of the secondary compounds, which pass through to the final stages. The results would be genomic DNA contaminated with polysaccharides, polyphenols, etc.</p>
<h3 id="ulmus-autumn-leaves">Ulmus autumn leaves</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/Ulmus-autumn-leaves.jpg" type="" alt="Ulmus-autumn-leaves"  /></p>
<p>I tried TNE (Tris, NaCl, EDTA) buffer as a pre-wash before CTAB for Ulmus species, but DNA was not precipitating well enough after keeping overnight at -20C. And quality, according to the NanoDrop, was not good either.</p>
<p>Washing with Sorbitol instead of TNE improved the yield and quality of genomic DNA but could have been better. This method is described in detail in the
<a href="https://doi.org/10.1371/journal.pone.0206085">Inglis et al. 2018</a>. I repeated both washes twice to discard the viscous supernatant.</p>
<h3 id="samples-in-isopropyl-alcohol-tne-pre-wash">Samples in Isopropyl alcohol (TNE pre-wash)</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/TNE-wash.jpg" type="" alt="TNE-wash"  /></p>
<h3 id="samples-in-isopropyl-alcohol-sorbitol-pre-wash">Samples in Isopropyl alcohol (Sorbitol pre-wash)</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/Sorbitol-wash.jpg" type="" alt="Sorbitol-wash"  /></p>
<p>More compounds (e.g., polysaccharides, polyphenolics) were carried over to this step using TNE compared to Sorbitol. This is visible in the agarose 1% gel images. The ladder is 1 kb.</p>
<h3 id="after-sorbitol-wash">After Sorbitol wash</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/after-sorbitol.jpg" type="" alt="after-sorbitol"  /></p>
<h3 id="after-tne-wash">After TNE wash</h3>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/after-TNE.jpg" type="" alt="after-TNE"  /></p>
<p>There is room for improvement, though. If you have to extract DNA from autumn leaves, try sorbitol wash! Other options would be from buds, cambium, or woods.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Diversity of Life</title>
      <link>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/diversity-of-life/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 19:36:13 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/diversity-of-life/</guid>
      <description></description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/virus.jpg" type="" alt="viruses"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/bacteria.jpg" type="" alt="bacteria"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/fungi.jpg" type="" alt="fungi"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/plants.jpg" type="" alt="plants"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/trees.jpg" type="" alt="trees.jpg"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/fishes.jpg" type="" alt="fishes.jpg"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/snakes.jpg" type="" alt="snakes.jpg"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/insects.jpg" type="" alt="insects.jpg"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/birds.jpg" type="" alt="birds.jpg"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/mammals.jpg" type="" alt="mammals.jpg"  /></p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/homo.jpg" type="" alt="homo"  /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>For Iranian Women - برای زنان ایران</title>
      <link>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/for-iranian-women/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Dec 2022 22:24:29 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/for-iranian-women/</guid>
      <description>Recent incidents about the deaths of people in Iran are disturbing. Killing, arresting, and threatening people is not how to treat Iran&amp;rsquo;s brave women and men. What a shame to arrest Taraneh Alidoosti, a citizen, mom of a nine-year-old daughter, and award-winning actress.
It is cowardly to shut internet access and block common communication apps aiming to isolate people from each other and the rest of the world. I am deeply upset about the current situation and stand with the people.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Recent incidents about the deaths of people in Iran are disturbing. Killing, arresting, and threatening people is not how to treat Iran&rsquo;s brave women and men. What a shame to arrest <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taraneh_Alidoosti#Arrest">Taraneh Alidoosti</a>, a citizen, mom of a nine-year-old daughter, and award-winning actress.</p>
<p>It is cowardly to shut internet access and block common communication apps aiming to isolate people from each other and the rest of the world. I am deeply upset about the current situation and stand with the people.</p>
<p>(Stop fire. We had enough&hellip;) آتیش کافیه به اندازه داشتیم</p>
<p>
  <img loading="lazy" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/1/14/Taraneh_Alidoosti%2C_The_Salesman_news_conference_%2813950311005853135%29.jpg?" alt="Taraneh Alidoosti"  title="Taraneh Alidoosti"  />
Image credit: <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Taraneh_Alidoosti">Wikipedia</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Welcome - First post</title>
      <link>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/welcome/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 23:28:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatanparast.xyz/posts/welcome/</guid>
      <description>With the plethora of &amp;lsquo;free&amp;rsquo; and &amp;lsquo;social&amp;rsquo; platforms for microblogging, a need for a personal blog or website seems redundant. I firmly believe in having an independent platform and not relying on ad-promoted giants. A private domain costs a few bucks annually, and hosting a website is easy and quick that can be done locally or on paid servers.
This static website has zero analytics, ads, or other nonsense. It should be responsive and fast on desktop or mobile.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>With the plethora of &lsquo;free&rsquo; and &lsquo;social&rsquo;  platforms for microblogging, a need for a personal blog or website seems redundant. I firmly believe in having an independent platform and not relying on ad-promoted giants. A private domain costs a few bucks annually, and hosting a website is easy and quick that can be done locally or on paid servers.</p>
<p>This static website has zero analytics, ads, or other nonsense. It should be responsive and fast on desktop or mobile.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
