<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>legumes on Home</title>
    <link>https://vatanparast.xyz/tags/legumes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in legumes on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 22:34:53 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://vatanparast.xyz/tags/legumes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Research</title>
      <link>https://vatanparast.xyz/research/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 May 2022 22:34:53 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://vatanparast.xyz/research/</guid>
      <description>Evolution of Legumes I have been studying legumes (Fabaceae) at various taxonomic levels. My master&amp;rsquo;s thesis was on the biosystematics of Trifolium L. (clover) in Iran, where there are over 40 species. Via international collaboration, I published the molecular phylogeny of Dalbergia L.f., a pantropical genus, in 2013. I also collaborated with the Legume Phylogeny Working Group and built species-level phylogeny of numerous genera such as Eriosema (DC.) Desv., Mucuna Adans.</description>
      <content:encoded><![CDATA[<h2 id="evolution-of-legumes">Evolution of Legumes</h2>
<p>I have been studying legumes (Fabaceae) at various taxonomic levels. My master&rsquo;s thesis was on the biosystematics of <em>Trifolium</em> L. (clover) in Iran, where there are over 40 species. Via international collaboration, I published the molecular phylogeny of <em>Dalbergia</em> L.f., a pantropical genus, in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1016/j.sajb.2013.07.001">2013</a>. I also collaborated with the <a href="https://doi.org/10.12705/661.3">Legume Phylogeny Working Group</a> and built species-level phylogeny of numerous genera such as <em>Eriosema</em> (DC.) Desv., <em>Mucuna</em> Adans., and <em>Pueraria</em> DC..</p>
<!-- raw HTML omitted -->
<p>At the Department of Botany at the Smithsonian Institution, USA, I applied phylogenomic methods to resolve the relationships between the Milletioid and Phaseoloid legumes using over 500 nuclear loci. As an example, the following image shows the gene recovery of 423 nuclear loci for 25 species. These gene sets can be used at various hierarchies across Fabaceae. You can find detailed information about them <a href="https://doi.org/10.6084/m9.figshare.c.4040372.v4">here</a> and the paper in <a href="https://doi.org/10.1002/aps3.1036">Applications in Plant Sciences</a>.</p>
<p><img loading="lazy" src="/images/500-loci.jpg" type="" alt="500-loci"  /></p>
<p> </p>
<h2 id="phylogeography-of-hyrcanian-forests">Phylogeography of Hyrcanian Forests</h2>
<p>At the University of Copenhagen, Denmark, I studied the phylogeography of tree species from the Hyrcanian forests in Iran. Hyrcanian forest is a UNESCO-listed <a href="https://whc.unesco.org/en/list/1584">world heritage</a> and harbors over 80 woody plants, some of which are relict species from <a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Arcto-Tertiary_Geoflora">Arco-Tertiary</a>. Despite its importance from an ecological and economic perspective, there are no comparative phylogeographic studies of these species. I use genome-wide SNPs to understand the genetic structure of populations in the Hyrcanian forests.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
